so let's compare what we need for the
conditional moves at what we need for
full predication so for the move
instructions that are conditional we
need a separate opcode that tells us
this is a conditional instruction
usually we have a separate opcode for
each particular condition so we need a
number of new opcode
for full predication we use the same
instructions that we use without
conditions
we add condition bits for full
predication however we add condition
bits to every instructions so every
instruction word contains some bits that
tell us what is the condition for
writing to the destination register for
example the intel itanium instruction
set has full predication and this is
what an add instruction would look like
it specifies the two source registers
the destination registers that this is
an ad and it has a field within the
instruction to specify the so-called
qualifying predicate that is where the
condition for doing the right to the r1
register will be found in the attained
iam instruction has 41 bits where the
least significant six bits specify what
the qualifying predicate is the
predicates in the Itanium are actually
small one bit registers so that you can
do a condition check and store the
result in this one bit register and then
really the six bits here tell you which
of the 64 bit conditional registers are
you gonna use to determine whether to
write to r1